MAYANK SINGHAI

MANAGER MARKETING

Marketing Manager with BE and +5 years of Experience in Cutting tools Industry and Heavy Machinery. Seeking to leverage my technical and professional expertise to learn and grow in the new role of Business development manager at your company

Experience

2016-01 present

Manager Marketing

Miranda Tools pvt ltd

Business development of Miranda Product i.e. Bi-Metal Band Saw Blade, MCBB, Power saw, Hack saw all India basis.

Providing After Sales Support and Service.

Understanding application of customer and complaints on regular basis. Conduct trials and suggest Application to Improve the Lost regain customer. Co-ordinate with Sales Branches all over pan India and Perform Trials at customer End.

Co-ordinate with Quality and Production Department to ensure the standard quality and timely delivery of material.

Regularly visit Branches and the customers for business development, Maintain relationship by giving them support information and necessary guidance. Schedule meetings and periodically visit to customer end & promoting our services.

Create and Manage customer database of old customers and new customers in Take all accounts of customer monthly quarterly and yearly.

Tracking market development and competitor activities. Branch wise SKU wise Budget Preparation, close eye on market share, Analysis of competitors activities.

2015-07 -2016-01

Sales & Application Engineer

MEBA India pvt ltd

Business Development of MEBA Products like Band Saw Blade And MEBA Band Saw Machines, Annular Cutter.

Business Development of RSA circular Saw Machine and MEBA Cutters. Providing after Sales Support and Service as we are sawing expert.

Regularly visit customers and dealers, Maintain relationship by giving them support information and necessary guidance.

Schedule meetings and periodically visit to our customer and promoting our service offering.

Create and Manage customer database of old customers and new Customer's in Ahmedabad, Rajkot extended to whole Gujarat.

Take all accounts of customer monthly quarterly and yearly.

Driving business growth through client's engagement.

2013-07 -

2015-07

Sales and Service Engineer

ITL Industries Ltd



Personal Info

Address

Ahmedabad

Phone

9727963603

E-mail

mayanksinghai999@gmail.com

Date of birth 1991-08-27

Skills

Computer Skills Advanced knowledge of MS Excel (macros, pivot tables, data visualization) Proficient in MS Access (creating and modifying databases, tables, queries and forms; reports advanced

Management Skills work
management, time management,
MS Office - expert knowledge of
entire suite

Adaptability worked on different

Teamwork - part of sales team who generated most revenue for the company

Designing of panel as per the requirement.

Electrical drawing using auto cad.

Learning the every logic of circular saw machine and servicing.

Learning every logic of band saw machine and servicing.

Commissioning of circular saw numeric control in Bharat forge Itd

(Pune), Rajkot etc.

Education

2009-10 -2013-06

Rajiv Gandhi Proudyogiki vishwavidalaya

BE in Electronics & Communication

(2009-2013) 74.2 %

2008-07 -

2009-03

Gyanodaya S.M.V.M CBSE School

12th

CBSE 68%

2006-07 -

2007-03

Gyanodaya S.M.V.M CBSE School

10th

CBSE 65%

2014-02

IIT KHARAGPUR

GATE-14

98 Percentile

2016

IIT KHARAGPUR

Online Course- 8 weeks

Structural communication & Sustainable Development

2017

IIT KHARAGPUR

Online Course- 12 weeks

Six Sigma